Shanthi Acharya

Product Design Manager

shanthi.s.acharya@gmail.com | 510-333-3372 http://www.shanthiacharya.com (pwd: designpower)

Hands on design manager with proven know-how to combine creativity, end user focus and business goals resulting in world-class design solutions. 15+ years of success delivering compelling user experience across web and mobile solutions for enterprise and consumer brands.

Work Experience

Workday Analytics | Product Design Manager | Apr 2020 – Present Design Lead | Jan 2019 – Apr 2020

 Manage a team of product designers helping shape the experience for Data platform products at Workday Analytics. Partner in all phases of the product development lifecycle with product management, UX research, engineering and tech writers. Early stage concept work and mentoring other designers in the end-to-end UX process.

Ellie Mae | Lead Interaction Designer | June 2016 – Dec 2018

Lead design efforts for Next Generation of Mortgage Enterprise
 Application with cross functional teams creating engaging and efficient
 experiences. Delivered UX architecture and patterns that transformed
 complex flows into simpler and efficient experiences for customers.

GE Digital | Staff Interaction Designer | May 2012 – June 2016

 Lead design & research efforts with multi disciplinary and international teams to deliver compelling user experiences for Industrial Internet Applications for projects across several GE businesses such as Asset Management, Field Service Application, Predictive Insights and Industrial eCommerce. Won 5 Above & Beyond awards for Expertise, Team Collaboration and Imagination in different projects.

Western Digital | Senior UX Designer | Jun 2010 - May 2012

 Lead designer for Western Digital Branded Products Group to deliver innovative design solutions for WD networked devices including Web, Mobile and TV experiences. Delivered Information architecture, task flows, wireframes and interactive prototype for rich media web UI for WD home storage devices.

UX Consultant | Nov 2009 - May 2010

 Created production quality interactive prototype for touch screen based tablet device targeted at education market using Adobe Flex. Worked with user researchers in planning and conducting usability studies with the prototype and provided design feedback to the team.

IBM | UX Designer Intern | Mar 2008 -Oct 2009

 IBM Mashup Center: Worked on Design & Usability testing of IBM Mashup Center Catalog to provide better integration experience across different components of Mashup center.

Intel | Senior Software Engineer | Oct 1999 – Mar 2008

 Benchmark software development and Application Performance Study on Intel processor performance with focus on user experience assessment and performance data analysis.

Education

M.S. Human Factors
San Jose State University

M.S. Computer Science
California State University, Hayward